[Music]
hey everyone welcome back to tips of the
trade
I'm Ava thought that this is my channel
where I talk about things related to the
entertainment industry and today I'm
gonna do something I have never done
before I'm gonna do a product review I
mentioned this in one of my other videos
about vocal health that there was a
product that I purchased really just on
a whim and it was amazing it like
changed my life and I feel obligated to
review this product and kind of tell
other people about it because like I
said I had never really heard of this I
tried it out because it was really just
working a lot and I had tons of gigs
this summer do you like that humble brag
I was just working so much but really I
was which is great but I was starting to
just feel the exhaustion in my voice and
so I went on Amazon
and it was in desperation looking for
something to help me and I found this
product called voice 37 there it is okay
now look when I first got this the Box
looks perfect this has been kicking
around my gig bag for like three months
so this isn't what the box came looking
like it was perfect and lovely but I
didn't want to show you the packaging it
is a liquid formula and I will talk a
little bit about how it's described and
then I will tell you how it affected me
when I was gigging it was amazing so
here is how it is described on Amazon
which is where I bought it it says oops
your voice voice 37 benefits improve
your resonance range camera and prevent
voice train eliminate or reduce vocal
problems hoarseness and dry cough help
clear improving phlegm during singing or
speeches strengthen and protect your
voice during ongoing use soothe your
strained sore tired vocal cords restore
and refresher
clarity lubricate and within your voice
reduces and prevents vocal challenges
boy does that sound great I think I had
all of the above when I bought this
product it comes in 2 ounce package for
$35 on Amazon and it's natural which is
great that's another awesome thing about
the product it's all like natural stuff
the ingredients are vegetable base no
alcohol
tell me what's not in it slippery elm
barton which I talked about as being an
ingredient that is used a lot in vocal
formulas and vocal remedies fennel seed
horseradish root time
celery seed and horehound herb I've
never heard of that before but I looked
it up and it is apparently an aromatic
herb in the mint family used for
digestion and cost that is the cost
remedy in this formula ok I want to talk
a little bit about the instructions
something in the instructions that's
kind of weird
okay instructions for use shake well
before use recommended dosage take one
to two times a day when needed you fill
approximately 3/4 of the dropper so that
is looks like 0.75 milliliters then you
can put it directly into your mouth or
you can mix it in two ounces of water
which is about that here's the crazy
part it tastes like nothing when you put
it into water it doesn't taste like
anything which is awesome because I was
expecting something like if it has an
effect it probably tastes disgusting
but no it didn't taste like anything and
even when you just put it directly in
your mouth it tastes kind of sweet like
slippery elm is sort of sweet it was
good best when take in two to three
hours before a performance and it lasts
12 hours or more it works particularly
well here is the weird part it works
particularly well when taken with a
piece of starch based food so I tried it
with like some crack
kurz and i guess it works it probably
helps with absorption or something I
don't know it suggests whole-wheat spelt
okay for your voice
drinking 10 to 12 cups of water a day is
a necessity which is true I've already
talked about that in other videos
not recommended for daily use I take
that to heart I'm not sure why this
isn't recommended for daily use but I'm
assuming there's a reason for that
so I would say this kind of product is
better for when you're having vocal
problems as a post is something that you
do on a regular basis before each
performance so if you're doing eight
shows a week at a Broadway show this
might not be the best thing to do every
single day before your show maybe just
do it if you have something going on
again I don't know why it says that but
I am the kind of person that I want to
take the risk I don't want to overdo it
I don't know if it will make it less
effective or if it will have some kind
of negative effect on my voice but I
don't want to do it every day okay so
let's get to the actual review I used
this product on a day where I was doing
my vocal warmup and that super scary
thing happened where I started getting
to my upper register and the notes were
just disappearing nothing was coming out
it was just phlegm and swollen messy I
don't know what was going on but nothing
was coming out so I really needed this I
took the two ounces of water suggestion
took it after 10 minutes I felt
incredibly thirsty so I needed to guzzle
like I think I drank two bottles of
water like back to back I just it just
made me super super thirsty the one time
I did and I didn't have a ton of water
available it actually had kind of an
opposite effect it made me a little bit
more dried out but if I drink the water
right after taking it it really does
have a lasting effect that lasted
throughout the entire gig all the way to
the end it was magical
I was singing every song all the high
notes
I felt the the notes were coming out
clear my whole range was there I felt
like it helped so much I was popping out
all the high notes all the high notes
were there and I was so grateful it is a
product that I have used multiple times
now and every time it has the same
effect but I do have to drink a lot of
water now I know what you're thinking
maybe it's not the product maybe you're
just not drinking enough water but I
don't think that's the case because
there have been times when I felt a
little something going off my voice and
I've just guzzle dwara to try to help
and it doesn't help the way that product
helped particularly in my upper register
that as I said was the issue when I was
warming up it was all the higher notes
were just missing they weren't coming
out and when I did the cake all there
felt super clear I felt great after the
gig really really really magical amazing
I do want to add this little footnote
though as magical as this product is
there is no magic pill that's going to
make you a better singer than you
actually are believe me I've looked
that I haven't found it yet this is the
kind of thing where it's going to get
you to sound your best so the things
that you know you're able to do the
songs that you know you're able to sing
on a good day it'll get you there again
to me that's how it affected me now am I
gonna take a dose and immediately sound
like Shoshana beam no but it helped me
sound my best it was magical I loved it
so there is my first product review I
don't know
that went if you have any questions
about it I'd love to try to answer them
for you
please subscribe comment come back again
I'll see you next time